

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · RESEARCHER · SOFTWARE DESIGNED

P.O Box 62891, Nairobi, 00200, Republic of Kenya

 [(+254) 70-226-2663 | ■ jaysonamati@gmail.com | ↑ https://0x-inf.github.io/ | ☑ jaysonamati | ☐ jaysonamati

"Wisdom Begins in Wonder."

Summary.

Problem Solving is my forte. The process of framing a problem in the right way, designing a solution, preferably technological and testing if it indeed solves the problem is one that i find joyful and exciting. Have been developing software related solutions to problems that i see around me and also ones that have been described to me. 5+ years of working with various technology stacks and in diverse problem domains.

Love to participate in tech communities and sharing knowledge and experience and contributing through writing to the wide array of information on the internet and open source projects. Always learning new tools and technologies along with novel frameworks of thought from the realm of mathematics. Interested in communicating with clarity on solutions to problems and also demonstrating an understanding of a particular problem. I'm also striving to being a Research mathematician.

Work Experience

Just 4 ClimateNairobi, Kenya

BACKEND ENGINEER & FOUNDING MEMBER & SMART CONTRACT DEVELOPER(PLUTUS)

Jun. 2023 - Present

Open Source Software, RikaResource

Nairobi, Kenya

PRIMARY CONTRIBUTOR & SOFTWARE ENGINEER & MATHEMATICAL RESEARCHER

Aug. 2022 - Present

- Designing Software for an autonomous Collective.
- Developing mathematical foundations for the peer to peer resource control hive
- Implementing a web platform using the ihp haskell framework and leveraging the shipnix deployment platform for nixOS based systems
- Integrating Formal Methods in the software development process to ensure high levels of program correctness using Agda
- Establishing a programming style guide for contributors

Color Corporation Limited.

Nairobi, Kenya

Dec. 2017 - Jun. 2021

- FOUNDING MEMBER & SOFTWARE ENGINEER
- Designed and Developed various android applications
- Integrated Payment Services for various platforms, in particular Mpesa Payments
- Established architecture for leveraging google places API for various use-cases
- Provisioned Firebase for monitoring, A/B testing, analytics, authentication, firestore, storage and cloud functions for the various mobile applications

Certificates

Jun. 2016 Android Developer, Emobilis Institute

Dec. 2017 Moringa School Programming bootcamp, Moringa School

Presentation

React Developers Kenya Meeting

Nairobi, Kenya

Nov. 2022

Presenter for <Functional Programming Concepts in React>

- Introduced the paradigm of Functional Programming to the audience
- · Showed the similarities in concepts between react and Functional Programming, particularly Haskell

Education

Chalmers University of Technology

Online

PhD course on Functional Programming and Climate Impact Research

Mar. 2024 - Present

- Effectively use Haskell and Agda for formalisation
- Understand a selection of topics in Climate Impact Research
- · Use functional programming specification / implementation / formalisation as a way of understanding new domains

IOG(IOG Education Kenya)

Nairobi, Kenya & Online

IOG BOOTCAMP KENYA

Zero to Productive Haskell and Smart Contract Developer

UON(University Of Nairobi)

Nairobi, Kenya

B.S. IN ECONOMICS AND STATISTICS

Jan. 2017 - Dec. 2021

Aug. 2023 - Oct. 2023

- Received a research based education from the institution
- Conducted Research on Inflation in order to receive degree
- Applied mathematical reasoning and statistical methods to model real world problems

Extracurricular Activity

Economics Debate Forum Nairobi, Kenya

MEMBER

Jun. 2018 - Mar. 2021

- Organized colloquia on economics matters
- Gave talks on using various software tools in python to do data analysis and visualizations

Google Developer Group: UON Chapter

Nairobi, Kenya

Jan. 2018 - Mar. 2020

• Gained exposure to the software industry through the live coding sessions and tutorials in meetings

- Attended various talks and presentations on Software related topics
- · Participated in discussions around programming and software development

Skills__

MEMBER & ATTENDEE

Mobile Android (Kotlin), Android (Java)

DevOps Docker, Kubernetes, GitHub Actions, ShipNix

Back-end Servant, Actix, Express, REST API

Front-end Elm, React, HTML5, TailwindCSS, Jetpack Compose numpy, scipy, Pandas, PyTorch, networkx, Jupyter

Programming Haskell, Rust, Javascript (Node.js), Julia, Python, JAVA, Kotlin, LaTeX

Languages Swahili, English, Kamba